[The Odd Jobs head to Ryugu Palace. Kamenashi,
whom they saved, leads them there.]
[The summer vacation special project:
The Ryugu Arc... Begins this week!!]
♪♪～
(新八)銀さん…｡
(銀時)なによ？
Gin-san...
What is it?!
いましたか？ 怪しい人｡
いねえな｡
Did you find the suspicious person?
He's not here.
水着も付けずに ｶﾒﾗ持って
ﾌﾟﾗﾌﾟﾗしてる人とかが➡
People who are not wearing swimsuits
and wandering around with cameras...
怪しいらしいです｡
女の子の水着姿を➡
are suspects. He's probably been secretly
taking pictures of girls in swimsuits.
隠し撮りしてるとみて
間違いないです｡
ああそう｡
ちゃんと探してるんでしょうね？
I see.
I hope you're really looking
for him. Really, I beg you.
頼みますよ ﾎﾝﾄ…｡
The peace of the beach
rests on our shoulders.
海の平和は
ﾎﾞｸらの肩にかかってるんですよ｡
しかし 海開きくらいで 毎年➡
That aside, everyone sure makes a big fuss
about the beach opening every year.
どいつもこいつも
はしゃぎやがって…｡
ﾊﾞｶなんじゃねえの？
What are they, stupid?
生物は皆
海で生まれたっていうでしょ｡
They say that all life forms
came from the sea.
無意識下で皆 母なる海を
求めてるらしいですよ｡
Apparently, everyone's unconsciously
yearning for mother ocean.
年に１回
竜宮城に里帰り ってか…｡
[Coast Guard Headquarters]
An annual return to Ryugu Palace, huh?
I'd like someone to take us there.
[Note: Ryugu Palace is the undersea palace of the dragon
god of the sea according to Japanese mythology.]
連れてってほしいもんだよ
ｵﾚたちも｡
あれ そういや 神楽ちゃんは？
Huh? Come to think of it,
where's Kagura-chan?
亀でも
探しにいったんじゃねえの？
She probably went to look for a turtle.
あれ？
あそこに人だかりができてる｡
Huh? People are gathering over there.
ん？ 神楽じゃねえか あれ｡
It's Kagura-chan, isn't it?
もめてるみたいです あれ
ちょっと…！
It looks like she got in a
fight. Let's take a look.
Huh? Don't think...
(神楽)あん？ ﾃﾒｴ
あんま なめてっと… あん？
I'll let you get away with this.
うお～!!
(亀梨)うわぁ！
Stand the hell up! That was
for Krillin. Next is...
[Note: Refers to Krillin from Dragon Ball.]
(神楽)立て こらぁ ああっ
今のは ｸﾘﾘﾝの分だ！
次は…｡
神楽ちゃ～ん！
Kagura-chan!
何やってんの～？
What are you doing?!
Are you all right?!
大丈夫ですか？
(亀梨)うぅ…｡
大丈夫なんですか？
亀なんですか？ これ｡
Are you all right?! Is he a turtle?
海で 亀いじめるなんて
何考えてんだよ 神楽ちゃん｡
What are you thinking, Kagura-chan?
How could you pick on a turtle
at the beach? That's abusive!!
暴挙だよ 暴挙！
つうか亀なのか？ これ｡
Is he really a turtle?
違うんです｡
この亀 さっきから➡
You've got it wrong. This turtle has
been filming us all this time.
私たちのこと
ｶﾒﾗで ずっと撮ってて…｡
つうか 亀なのか？ これ｡
Is he really turtle?
この子は 私たちのこと
助けてくれたんです｡
This girl helped us.
ｴｯﾍﾝ！
So did you film them?
何？ おたく撮ったの？
撮ってないすよ｡
I wasn't filming them.
ﾎﾞｸ ｺﾝﾌﾞ撮ってただけだし｡
I was just filming kelp.
Liar!! You were only following
around girls!!
ｳｿつけよ！ 女の子のあとばっか
つけ回してたくせに！
撮ってないすよ｡ ﾎﾝﾄ
いいがかりやめてくんないすか｡
I wasn't filming them. Honestly, could
you stop making things up?
迷惑なんすけど｡
It's really annoying.
わかりました｡
じゃ すいませんけど➡
All right. Then, excuse me,
ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵｶﾒﾗの中身だけ
ﾁｪｯｸさせてもらえます？
but may I check the contents
of that video camera?
No. I told you that I didn't film them.
This is an invasion of privacy.
いやっすよ！ ｵﾚ 撮ってないって
言ったじゃないすか｡
ﾌﾟﾗｲﾊﾞｼｰの侵害っすわ｡
ちょ ちょっ…！
H-Hey!
撮ってないなら見せられるでしょ｡
If you didn't film them, then you
can show it to us, can't you?
濡れ衣も晴れるし 見せなさいよ!!
It'll clear you of any suspicion.
Gimme that!!
ああっ…！
あっ あの…
基本 ｺﾝﾌﾞしか撮ってないすけど➡
Umm... I usually only film kelp, but there
may be girls on the sides of the videos.
ちょっとは画面の端に 女の子も
入っちゃってるかもしんないす｡
それは ｾｰﾌですよね？
それは ありですよね？
That's safe, right?
That's okay, right?
No, that's not it. That's not it.
いや 違うんですよ｡
それ 違うんすよ｡
あの… 実はﾎﾞｸ 自作で
ﾀﾞｼﾞｬﾚのﾋﾞﾃﾞｵ作ってて 亀がｶﾒﾗで…｡
Actually, I was just filming
a swimsuit commercial.
It's a company camera, ya know.
ほわちゃ～!!
うがっ…！
[Coast Guard Headquarters]
住所は？
Where do you live?
あの… すいません！
Umm, I'm sorry. Could you
please not not tell my family?
家族に言うのだけは
勘弁してもらえないすか？
もうすぐ 嫁さん産卵なんですよ｡
My wife is going to be laying eggs soon.
ﾃﾞﾘｹｰﾄな時期なんです｡
She's very sensitive at the moment.
そりゃ 泣きながら
卵産むことになるね｡
She'll just have to shed tears
as she lays her eggs.
いや ﾎﾝﾄ
ﾏｼﾞですいませんって！
I really am sorry. I really
won't do it again.
It's the truth! I swear on kelp!! Really!
もう ﾎﾝﾄにやらないんで！
ﾎﾝﾄ ｺﾝﾌﾞに誓います！ ﾏｼﾞで！
なに その誓い方
亀の世界で流行ってんの？
What kind of oath is that? Is that
popular in the turtle world?
こんなことで もし
お腹の卵に何かあったら➡
If something were to happen to the
eggs in her belly because of this...
ｺﾝﾌﾞの川流れっすわ！
Even kelp can be washed
away by the river currents.
何それ？ ことわざ？
全部 ｺﾝﾌﾞと絡めるの？
What is that, a proverb?
Are they all kelp related?
もう ｺﾝﾌﾞがあったら食べたい！
I wish I could eat kelp!!
穴があったら入りたい的な
あれですか？
Is that like "I wish I could
crawl into a hole"?
酢ｺﾝﾌﾞならあるよ｡
あ… すいません｡
I have some pickled seaweed.
Oh, thanks.
あっ 銀さん
所持品に免許あります｡
Oh Gin-san, he has a license
amongst his possessions.
船舶免許ですね｡
亀なら泳げよ！
It's a boat license.
If you're a turtle--just swim!
え～ 住所は
竜宮城三丁目 ２ｰ５ｰ３…➡
3-chome, 2-5-3,
ﾒｿﾞﾝｺﾝﾌﾞ305号… 竜宮城？
Maison Kelp, Room 305...
Ryugu Palace?
Ryugu Palace? You live
in Ryugu Palace?
竜宮城って竜宮城に住んでんの!?
あ… はい｡ 実は ｵﾚ
竜宮城のｶﾞｲﾄﾞやってんすけど…｡
Oh... Yes. Actually I'm a guide
at the Ryugu Palace...
ﾏｼﾞでかぁ～？ えっ あんの？
竜宮城 ﾏｼﾞであんの!?
Really?! Huh?! It exists? Ryugu
Palace really exists?!
え？ ありますけど普通に…｡
Huh? It ordinarily exists...
["Summer Vacation is the Most
Fun Right Before It Begins"]
Long, long ago... Urashima
caught a voyeuristic turtle...
[Note: Urashima Taro is the story of a fisherman who rescues a turtle and is rewarded with a visit to Ryugu Palace under the sea.]
♬(神楽)｢むかし～ むかし～
浦島は～｣
♬｢盗撮した亀をつかまえて～｣
♬｢竜宮城に行ってみれば～…｣
(亀梨)やめてくんないすか？
When he went to Ryugu Palace...
Could you stop that? Could
you stop singing that song?
その歌 やめてくんないかな｡
伝承されたら やばいんで…｡
It would be bad if it became folklore.
(神楽)ｷｬﾎ～！
竜宮城で夏休みｱﾙ！
Yahoo! We get to spend summer
vacation at Ryugu Palace!
I never thought Ryugu Palace
actually existed.
いやぁ 竜宮城が
実在していたなんて…｡
じゃあ 浦島 太郎も
ﾎﾝﾄにいたんですか？
Does that mean Taro Urashima
actually existed?
ええ ﾎﾞｸは知らないんすけど➡
Yes. I don't know him,
but a guest the first turtle brought
over was called Urashima-san.
初代の亀が 連れてきたお客さんが
浦島さんとかで… 以来ﾎﾞｸらは➡
We've called all of our guests
"Urashima-san" ever since.
お客さんのことは みんな
浦島さんって呼ぶんす｡
聞きました？ 銀さん！
ﾎﾞｸら 浦島さんだって！
Did you hear that, Gin-san?!
We're Urashima-san!!
すごくないですか？
歴史に名を刻みましたよ！
Isn't that amazing? We've
left our mark in history!!
どうでもいいけど さっきから
お客さん お客さんって…➡
This isn't really important, but you've
been referring to us as guests.
まさか
金とるつもりじゃねえだろうな？
You're not going to take money
from us, are you?
めっそうもないっす！
竜宮城は たしかに➡
Of course not!!
Ryugu Palace is indeed a paradise that
only chosen celebrities can visit.
選ばれた ｾﾚﾌﾞのみが
訪れることができる桃源郷｡
どれだけ 大枚をはたこうと
入ることのできない海の聖地です｡
It's the sea's holy land and
cannot be entered no matter how
much money you pay. But...
しかし 亀は こう見えて
義理を通す仁義の生き物｡
Turtles, despite their looks, are honorable
creatures that fulfill their duties.
Repaying favors like the surging and
receding waves is the law of the sea.
寄せては返す波が如く…➡
受けた恩は
きっちり返すが海の掟！
"Despite their looks"? There
aren't any turtles like you.
こう見えてったって
お前みたいな亀 いねえよ｡
皆さんには 今回 特別
ﾄﾞﾘﾝｸ飲み放題ｻｰﾋﾞｽ券を…｡
As a special offer...
I'll give you a complimentary
all-you-can-drink voucher...
(２人)ﾀﾀﾞにしろよ！
Make it free!!
わかりました｡ 今回 特別➡
All right. As a special offer...
ﾎﾟｲﾝﾄｶｰﾄﾞに ｽﾀﾝﾌﾟが２倍つきます！
I'll double the stamps on your point card.
(２人)ﾀﾀﾞにしろよ!!
Make it free!!
わかりました｡ ﾛｰｼｮﾝつけます…｡
All right. I'll rub lotion on you for free!
[Note: He's holding erotic massage lotion.]
(２人)何の店だよ！
What kind of shop are you?!
それはそうと これいつになったら
竜宮に着くんだ？
Anyway, how long will it
take to get to Ryugu?
かれこれ ２時間は
海を ただよっているぞ｡
We've been drifting in the ocean
for about two hours.
お前 船舶免許持ってんだろ！
You have a boat license, don't you?
Don't you have a faster boat?!
もっと ﾌﾞﾜ～っといける
船 持ってねえのかよ！
I got into an accident and killed
a dolphin. I'm on trial now.
(亀梨)以前 ｲﾙｶと人身事故
起こして今 裁判中なんすよ｡
How many times have
you been convicted?!
ｱﾝﾀ 前科何犯!?
おいおい 勘弁してくれよ！
Come on. Give me a break.
これじゃあ 玉手箱開ける前に
じぃさんになっちまうぜ！
At this rate, I'll become an old man before
I even open the treasure chest.
Hey, what's with that cruiser?
おい… 何だ あのｸﾙｰｻﾞｰ｡
あっ あれは…！
Th-That's...
姉上！ 九兵衛さん!!
Sis!! Kyubei-san!!
(お妙)あら～ 新ちゃん
どうしたの こんな海の真ん中で？
Oh, Shin-chan, what are you doing
out in the middle of the ocean?
You, two! Why are you here?
姉上こそ どうしたんですか？
今日は 九兵衛さんとｼｮｯﾋﾟﾝｸﾞじゃ？
I thought you were out shopping
with Kyubei-san.
(亀宮)お妙ちゃん 九ちゃん
いい ｶｼﾞｷﾏｸﾞﾛが釣れたよ｡
Otae-chan...
[Note: Parody of Japanese
actor, Tatsuya Umamiya.]
Kyu-chan...
I caught a nice swordfish.
Shall I clean it...
on our way to Ryugu?
竜宮への道すがら さばこうか？
Wh-What kind of turtle is that?!
な なんだ！ あの亀は～!!
He's really cool!! He has
a golden sheen to him!!
(神楽)超かっけぇ～！
黒光りしてるしてるｱﾙﾖ!!
He caught a swordfish!
He has chest hair!!
ｶｼﾞｷ釣ってるよ！胸毛生えてるよ!!
つうか あれ亀なの？
Is he really a turtle?
あ 姉上！ まさか姉上たちも！
S-Sis, could it be that you're also...
(九兵衛)実は 彼の娘が悪い男に
ひっかかっているところを➡
We happened to save his
daughter from bad men.
偶然 助けてな
いいと言っているのに➡
He was insistent on inviting us to Ryugu Palace
even though we said he didn't have to.
竜宮城に
招待すると言って聞かんのだ｡
稀代の悪だね ありゃ
そろそろ出るよ！
They were a rare brand of wicked men.
Let's get going. Ryugu Palace
gets crowded around this time.
竜宮城 この時期 込むから
急がないと｡
We must hurry.
あぁ はい｡
Oh, yes.
(お妙)じゃあ 新ちゃん みんな！
何をしてるのか知らないけど➡
Well, Shin-chan, I don't know what you all are doing,
but it's dangerous and you should return to land.
危ないから
そろそろ 陸に戻るのよ｡
H-Hey, wait...
ちょ ちょっと待って！
姉上 ﾎﾞｸらも乗せて～!!
Sis, let us on, too!!
Sis!!
(神楽)ｱﾈｺﾞ～！
Hey!!
おぃ～！ どういうことだ!!
何で 亀が複数存在してんだ!?
What's the meaning of that? Why
is there more than one turtle?!
そう簡単には 竜宮には
行けないんじゃないのかよ!!
I thought it wasn't that easy
to go to Ryugu Palace!!
なんだ あの亀は！
なんだ この差は!!
What's the deal with that turtle?!
Why is there such a difference?!
Gin-san, now's not the
time to be saying that.
銀さん
言ってる場合じゃないです！
He said that Ryugu Palace is going
to be crowded!! We've got to hurry.
竜宮城 込むって
言ってましたよ！ 急がないと｡
Damn it!!
くそだら～！ 負けてたまるか
ｵﾚたちの 夏休み!!
We can't let them outdo
our summer vacation!!
♪♪～
Wh-What the hell is this?!
なんじゃこりゃあ！
あっ あれは!!
Oh! That's...
(神楽)ﾏﾀﾞｵだぁ～！
おい なんだ あの亀｡
It's Madao!!
Hey, what's with that turtle?
絶対 誰にもいじめられね～よ！
あんな亀｡
No one would ever pick on that turtle.
(長谷川)よう 銀さん ｵﾚ崖から
身を投げようとしたらな➡
Hey, Gin-san, this turtle saved me when
I was about to jump off a cliff.
この亀に救われて
今 竜宮城に行くところなんだ｡
He's taking me to Ryugu Palace now.
助けるどころか
助けられてるんですけど あの人｡
He didn't save the turtle,
but was saved instead.
(亀艦長)長谷川さん
いいｽｶﾞｼｶｵが 手に入った｡
Hasegawa-san, I caught
a nice Shikao Suga.
[Note: Wordplay on Kajiki Maguro (swordfish)
and Suga Shikao (musician).]
竜宮への道すがら さばくか｡
Why don't we clean it
on the way to Ryugu?
What's a Shikao Suga?! How
are you going to clean that?!
ｽｶﾞｼｶｵって何だよ！
どう さばくんだよ!!
Captain!!
(亀船員)艦長！
上空に飛行物体が…！
なに!?
There's something flying above us...
What?!
(亀艦長)
ﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｶな！ あれは… まさか!!
I-Impossible. That's... It can't be...
♪♪～
(亀艦長)巨大な亀…｡
It's a giant turtle.
♪♪～
That's a soft-shelled turtle, isn't it?
(亀船員)あれ ｽｯﾎﾟﾝですね｡
(亀艦長)ｽｯﾎﾟﾝだな…｡
It's a soft-shelled turtle.
微妙に間違ってるんですけど｡
いや 待て｡
That's slightly inaccurate.
No, wait, we're riding in a rowboat
for transportation. His guide is...
乗り物は ｵﾚたちだってﾎﾞｰﾄだぜ
ｶﾞｲﾄﾞは…｡
♪♪～
いや 間違ってんですけど…｡
No, that's totally inaccurate...
[Note: Refers to Momotaro, a
hero from Japanese folklore.]
That's the wrong folktale.
昔話 間違ってんですけど！
Gintoki, I never expected to see
you here. What a coincidence.
(桂)銀時 こんなところで
会うとは奇遇だな｡
ｵﾚは ｷﾋﾞ団子をいただいた礼に➡
In return for giving them millet dumplings,
they're taking me to Tianzhu.
[Note: Millet dumplings are from the Japanese folktale of "Momotaro" and Tianzhu is from the Chinese legend "Journey to the West."]
これから天竺に向かうところでな｡
どこの国の昔話!?
What country is that folktale from?!
Fire!!
撃て～！
竜宮城に行くのは 長谷川さんだ!!
Hasegawa-san's the one who's
going to go to Ryugu Palace!
生きる希望をなくしたﾏﾀﾞｵに
光を与えてやるんだ～！
Madao has lost hope. I'm
going to give him a light!!
誰が 竜宮城など行くか！
Who'd want to go to Ryugu Palace?!
我らが目指すは 天竺だ！
ねえよ んなもん！
We're going to Tianzhu!!
That doesn't exist!!
♪♪～
You bastards!!
ﾃﾒｴら！ 海の帝王と
恐れられる ｵﾚの前で➡
I'm the feared Emperor of the Sea.
暴れるとは いい度胸だ！
You've got some nerve, getting
rowdy in front of me!!
全員 たっちゃん漬けの
重しにしてやらぁ！
I'll turn you all into weights
for making Tatchan-zuke!!
[Note: "Tatchan-zuke" is a brand of Japanese pickles
owned by Tatsuo Umemiya, a Japanese actor.]
H-Hey, wait!!
ちょっ ちょっと待って！
♪♪～
なんで!?
竜宮城に来たのに➡
Why?!
We just wanted to go to Ryugu
Palace. Why does this...
have to happen to us?!
こんな目に あわなきゃ
いけないんだぁ～！
(波の音)
ここは…｡
Is this...
竜宮城…？
Ryugu Palace?
＜ そこは
竜宮城などではなかった…＞
This wasn't Ryugu Palace.
みんな～！ 銀さ～ん
神楽ちゃ～ん 亀梨さん!!
Everyone! Gin-san, Kagura-chan,
Kamenashi-san!
＜ そこには 豪勢な料理も
美しい舞姫も➡
Here...
There wasn't any extravagant food, beautiful
dancers, or Otohime-sama.
乙姫様もいなかった＞
♪♪～
＜ﾎﾞｸの 最悪の夏休みが
始まろうとしていた＞
My...
worst summer vacation
was about to begin.
あぁ～！
♪♪～
[Gorilla News]
((ﾊﾟｲﾛｯﾄ:おい あれ 見ろ｡
(ﾊﾟｲﾛｯﾄ)ん？
Hey, look at that!
♪♪～
(ｱﾅｳﾝｻｰ)え～ 先日 無人島から
救出された人物は➡
We have determined that the
person who was rescued
60年前 遭難し
行方不明とされていた➡
from the deserted island the other day
is Shinpachi Shimura-san,
志村 新八さん 志村 新八さんで
あることが判明しました｡
who had gone missing sixty years ago.
[60 years ago]
[Shinpachi Shimura-san]
[Current]
(記者)恐縮ですが志村さん！
Excuse me, Shimura-san, but how did
you survive on that deserted island?
無人島では どのように
生活していたんですか？
(記者)何を食べていたんですか？
What did you eat?
(記者)どんなことを
思っていましたか？
What did you think about?
Wasn't there any way to escape?
(記者)脱出の方法とかは
なかったのですか？
(記者)今 いちばん したいことは
何ですか？
What do you want to do
the most right now?
♪♪～
銀さんたちに… 会いたい…｡
I want to see Gin-san and the others.
♪♪～
[Odd Jobs Gin]
[Lingerie Pub]
よっ お客さん
入ってきます？
Hey, sir, want to come in?
We have a lot of cute girls.
かわいい娘 いっぱいだよ！
好きでしょ ﾊﾟﾌﾊﾟﾌ!!
You'd like to have some
fun, wouldn't you?
誰も いない…｡
There isn't anyone...
みんな いない…｡
Everyone's gone...
どこにも いない…｡
They're not anywhere...
ﾎﾞｸは 一人…｡
I'm alone...
世界で 一人…))
I'm alone in the world...
うわぁぁ～!!
ﾊｧﾊｧ… ﾊｧﾊｧ…｡
《夢から覚めても
ﾎﾞｸは一人だった…｡
I was alone even when I
awoke from my nightmare.
浦島 太郎は 竜宮城で➡
Taro Urashima grew old while living
the fast life in Ryugu Palace.
放蕩の限りを尽くし
老人となったが➡
ﾎﾞｸは 竜宮城に着く前に➡
But I'm going to grow old alone in this place
without ever reaching Ryugu palace.
こんなところで一人
老人になっていくのか…｡
いや 老いるどころか
生き残ることができるのか？
No, I'm not sure I can even
survive, let alone grow old.
まして 誰かが
救出してくれる保障もない…｡
Furthermore, there's no guarantee
that anyone will rescue me.
いかん いかん… 一人でいると
弱気になってしまう》
No, no. I get depressed
when I'm by myself.
《ﾎﾟｼﾞﾃｨﾌﾞだ！
I need to think positive!!
こんなときこそ
ﾎﾟｼﾞﾃｨﾌﾞになれ！ 新八!!
You need to think positive at
times like this, Shinpachi!!
きっと銀さんたちも生きてる！
I'm sure that Gin-san and
the others are alive.
必ず 助けに来てくれるはずだ！
I'm sure they'll come to save me.
それまで
一人ででも がんばらねば！
Until then, I need to do
my best by myself.
ﾎﾟｼﾞﾃｨﾌﾞになれ 新八！
Think positive, Shinpachi.
世界とは 己の心を映す鏡だ！
The world is just a reflection
of your heart.
心のもち方ひとつで➡
One thought can change the
way you see the world.
世界は 何色にも
その色を変えるんだ！
むしろ この 状況を楽しめ 新八！
If anything, enjoy this predicament,
Shinpachi.
ここは無人島
ここまでの完璧な孤独は➡
This is a deserted island!!
There aren't many opportunities to experience
such complete solitude.
そう味わえるものではないぞ！》
♪♪～
《心が一気に
軽くなるのを感じていた｡
My heart suddenly feels lighter.
そして ﾎﾞｸは 気づいた｡
I realized that it wasn't clothes I had discarded,
but rather my mental armor.
ﾎﾞｸが脱ぎ捨てたのは
着物じゃない…｡
心の鎧だったんだと…｡
心をすり減らす 日常のなかで
ﾎﾞｸたちは いつのまにか➡
Our daily lives wear us down.
We end up placing heavy armor around our
hearts in order to get by without being hurt.
自らの心に 重い鎧を
着せてしまっていたんだ｡
傷つかないように
うまく生きるために…》
What are we afraid of?
《ﾎﾞｸらは いったい
何を恐れていたんだろう｡
鎧という壁を取り払った今
すべてを さらけ出した今➡
Now that I've removed my barrier,
now that I've let everything loose,
裸の心を何もかもが
優しく包んでいく…｡
my naked heart tenderly
accepts everything.
心が 風にとけていく…｡
My heart melts in the wind.
My body melts into nature.
体が 自然に とけていく｡
木が 水が 太陽が
すべてが ﾎﾞｸの中にあった！
The trees, the water, and the
sun were all within me.
そうだ ﾎﾞｸは この星の一部であり
星は ﾎﾞｸの一部だったんだ！
Yes. I am a part of this planet,
and this planet is a part of me.
いつのまにか 孤独感は
どこかに 吹き飛んでいた｡
Before I knew it, my sense of
loneliness had slipped away.
恐れるものなんて何もなかった｡
I had nothing to fear.
ﾎﾞｸは… 一人じゃない！》
I'm...
Not alone...
《ほんとに一人じゃなかった》
I really wasn't alone.
S-Someone was here.
いたんだ…｡
Y-You washed up here, too,
huh Hasegawa-san?
長谷川さんも
流れ着いてたんですね｡
(長谷川)さっきのは お互い
見なかったことにしようぜ｡
Let's ignore what we
were doing just now.
そうですね｡
Yeah.
完全に一人だと思ってたから➡
I thought that I was completely alone.
地球上に もうｵﾚしか
いないくらいのつもりで➡
I just let loose as if I was the
only person in the world.
ﾌﾙｽﾛｯﾄﾙで
すべてを さらけ出してたから…｡
いや こんな機会
確かに ないですもんね｡
Well, opportunities such
as this don't really exist.
波ぁ～っ!!
Ka-me-ha-me-ha!!
[Note: Parody of Dragon Ball]
か～め～は～め～ 波ぁ～!!
なんか違うな…
もうちょい あれだな｡
Something's wrong. Maybe I should
do it with a little more oomph.
か～め～は～め～！
Ka-me-ha-me...
♪♪～
ｵﾚたち 何も見てないから｡
We didn't see anything.
すまねえ…
完全に一人だと思ってたから➡
Thanks. I thought I was
completely alone.
全力で練習できると思って…｡
I thought I could practice
to my heart's content.
(手拍子)
Yeah!!
♪♪(お妙)｢ﾍｲ!!
あの娘は 太陽のｺﾏﾁｯ ｴﾝｼﾞｪｰ｣
That girl is a lovely angel from
the sun! Just a little wild! Say!
[Note: Lyrics to the B'z (a Japanese band)
song, Taiyo no Komachi Angel.]
♪♪｢やや乱れてYO ｾｲ！｣
ﾊｯ！
あの… B'zは みんな好きだからさ
恥ずかしがることねえよ｡
Umm... Everyone likes B'z. There's
nothing to be embarrassed about.
ずっと ﾄｯﾌﾟ走ってますもんね！
Th-They're always at
the top of the charts.
♪♪～
(九兵衛)あっ… あぁ…｡
わかる わかる…
人に見せたかったよね あれ｡
I understand. She wanted
to show that to someone.
奇跡的だったよね あれ｡
That was miraculous, wasn't it?
(神楽)あの雲！
絶対 中に ﾗﾋﾟｭﾀあるね!!
That cloud... Laputa's got to be in there!!
[Note: Refers to Laputa: Castle in the Sky.]
みんな思うわよ でかい雲見たら…
恥ずかしくないわよ｡
Everyone thinks that when
they see a huge cloud.
There's nothing embarrassing about that.
That girl is a lovely angel from the sun!
♪♪(桂)｢あの娘は
太陽のｺﾏﾁｯ ｴﾝｼﾞｪｰ｣
(桂)や… やや？
What's this?
あの雲… 絶対 中に➡
That cloud... There's got to be a crystallized
Crystal Takigawa in there.
[Note: Christel Takigawa is
a Japanese newscaster.]
滝川 ｸﾘｽﾀﾙの結晶が あると見た！
(桂)しまった！ ＳＯＳの途中で
止まってしまった！
Oh no. I stopped in the middle of "SOS"!
はっ！
なんでだよ～!?
What the-?!
I can't understand any of his actions!
一つ足りとも
理解できねえよ 行動が！
共感できねえよ！
なんだ!? これ！
I can't sympathize with
him. What is this?!
なんで これを
守ろうとしてんだよ！
Why was he trying to save this?
It's miraculous isn't it? It looks
exactly like Crystal Takigawa.
(桂)奇跡だろ これ！
滝川 ｸﾘｽﾀﾙ ｿｯｸﾘではないか！
What do you mean by
Crystal Takigawa?!
だから 何なんだよ！
滝川 ｸﾘｽﾀﾙって!!
奇跡的なのは
ﾃﾒｴの ﾊﾞｶさ加減だろ!!
What's miraculous is your idiocy!!
小便が 途中で切れてしまってな｡
I ran out of piss halfway.
誰か もよおしている者は
いないか？
Does anyone have to
go to the bathroom?
Why does it have to be in piss?!
なんで 小便ｵﾝﾘｰ!?
Anyway, how much did you piss?
つうか お前！
小便 どんだけ出たんだよ！
I'm surprised you drew
something this big!
よく こんな でかいの書けたな!!
I was influenced by Inoue
sensei's commercial.
井上 雄彦先生のＣＭに
影響されてな｡
Inoue sensei would never do this!!
井上先生 こんなことしねえよ!!
なんてこった…｡
全員 竜宮城に行く船 壊されて➡
This is terrible.
Our boats headed to Ryugu
Palace were destroyed
この 無人島に
流れ着いちまったってのか？
and we ended up on this deserted island.
It's Tianzhu, not Ryugu.
(桂)竜宮じゃない！ 天竺だ！
ｵﾒｴは 黙ってろ！
You be quiet.
(お妙)みんな 無事なだけでも
よかったじゃないの｡
It's great that everyone's all right.
なにが よかったんだよ｡
What's so great about this?
脱出する船も
助けを求める 連絡手段も➡
We don't have a boat to escape
in or any way to call for help,
not to mention food and shelter.
What are we going to do?
ﾒｼも家も ねえんだぞ！
これから どうするってんだい？
これだけ 頭数が揃ってれば
無人島でも なんとかなるさ｡
With this many of us, we'll manage
on this deserted island.
さしあたって 考えねばいかんのは
島からの 脱出手段｡
For now, we need to think of a way
to get off this island and
how to survive until then.
そして
脱出するまでの 生活方法だ｡
いや その前に ﾘｰﾀﾞｰを ｵﾚに
決めといたほうがいいだろう｡
Before we do, you should probably
choose me as your leader.
なんで 最初から
お前に決まってんだよ！
Why are you already the leader?
まず ﾘｰﾀﾞｰを決める方法を考える
ﾘｰﾀﾞｰを 考えよう｡
First, we should choose a leader to
decide how we'll choose a leader.
じゃあ まず ﾘｰﾀｰを決める方法を
決めるﾘｰﾀﾞｰを 決めるﾘｰﾀﾞｰを…｡
Then first, we should choose a leader
who will choose the leader who will
decide how we'll choose a leader.
おい！ めんどくせえよ!!
世の中 ﾘｰﾀﾞｰだらけになるわ！
Hey, this is really tedious!! Our world
will become filled with leaders!!
This is a bother, so Hasegawa-san
is good enough, right?
もう めんどくせえから
長谷川さんで いいだろう｡
He's the oldest.
年長だし 無人島でくらい
ｲｷがらせてやろうや｡
We should let him do what he
wants on this deserted island.
(長谷川)ｲﾔな言い方
すんじゃねえよ！
Don't say that in such an annoying
way! I don't want to be the leader!!
(長谷川)
願い下げだよ そんなﾘｰﾀﾞｰ！
That's right. Madao is best left in charge
of opening and closing curtains.
(神楽)そうね！ ﾏﾀﾞｵは せいぜい
ｶｰﾃﾝ開け閉め係くらいで いいｱﾙ！
(長谷川)なに その
どうでも よさそうな係！
Why am I in charge of something
that doesn't even matter?!
(長谷川)ｶｰﾃﾝなんて
どこにも ねえだろうが!!
There aren't even any
curtains anywhere!!
(神楽)人生のｶｰﾃﾝを閉める
係ｱﾙよ～！
You're in charge of closing
the curtains on your life.
Are you telling me to die?!
This girl is telling me to die!!
(長谷川)死ねってか!?
死ね！ って 言ってるよ この子！
What we need right now is
food and a place to sleep.
早急に必要なのは 食料と寝床｡
それに まず 何をおいても
島を探索せねば 始まらん｡
Also, we can't do anything unless
we explore this island.
今日のところは 食事班 寝床班➡
For today we shall split into four groups:
the food team, the shelter team,
探索班 ｶｰﾃﾝ係の
４つの班に 分かれて…｡
the exploration team, and
the curtains team...
We don't need anyone
in charge of curtains!!
(長谷川)ｶｰﾃﾝ係は いらねえよ!!
I want to be on the food team.
I'll cook with the utmost care.
は～い！ 私 食事班が いいです！
腕に よりをかけるわ！
よ～し！
班を １つ増やしてくれ！
All right, make one more team-the
chemical poisoning team.
化学毒殺班だ！
(殴る音)
Poison!
(長谷川)おら！
釣ってきてやったぜ！
Look. I caught these.
あら！ すごいわ 長谷川さん！
Oh my! That's amazing, Hasegawa-san!!
ﾍﾍｯ… こう見えても 海の男でね｡
I may not look it, but
I'm a man of the sea.
枝と餌さえ ありゃ
こんなもん 朝飯前よ！
As long as I have a pole
and bait, this is nothing.
すごいわ～｡
神様って どんな虫けらにも➡
That's amazing!
God gives merits to even the
most worthless of people.
取り柄を 与えてくれるんですね｡
あぁ… 神様 褒めてたの？
So you were praising God...
でもね…
食材は あっても 調理が…｡
But even if we have ingredients,
we can't cook...
(お妙)火が おこせないんです｡
いろいろ やってみたんですけど｡
We can't start a fire. I've tried everything.
(長谷川)いろいろ やったって…
これ 完全に 遊んでたよね？
Tried everything? Looks more
like you were fooling around.
(長谷川)碁を 打ってたよね？
(お妙)お父上が 健在の頃は➡
You were playing go.
When my father was still alive,
よく ｵｾﾛや碁盤を囲み
火花を散らせたものだわ｡
we'd gather around the othello
or go board and start a fire.
(長谷川)つかねえよ！
そんなんで 火！
You can't start a fire that way!!
そうだわ！ 長谷川さんって
ﾀﾊﾞｺ 吸われてましたよね？
Oh yeah, you were smoking, weren't
you? Do you have a lighter?
ﾗｲﾀｰとかは？
悪い…｡
Sorry, I dropped it in the ocean.
海で 落としちまった…｡
I was desperate to save
these sunglasses.
このｸﾞﾗｻﾝ 守るのに 必死でね…｡
そうですか… 困ったわね…｡
I see. That's problematic.
ｵﾚも ﾀﾊﾞｺ 吸いたくて
まいってんだよ…｡
I really want a cigarette.
Do something, Otae-chan.
なんとかしてくれよ お妙ちゃん｡
そうだわ！
Oh!! I know.
長谷川さん！ ちょっと そのｸﾞﾗｻﾝ
貸していただけます？
Hasegawa-san, could you
lend me your sunglasses?
なに？ どうすんの？
What? What are you going to do?
名案が｡
ちょっと 見ててくださいな｡
I just got a great idea... Just watch.
おいおい… 言っとくけど
ﾚﾝｽﾞ代わりにして➡
Just to let you know,
it's probably impossible to start a fire
using those lenses and sunlight.
太陽の光で 火 つけるとか
たぶん ﾑﾘだぜ？
(ｻﾝｸﾞﾗｽを割る音)
You were going to break them?!
壊すんか～い!!
(長谷川)しかも
火 持ってんじゃねえか！
Furthermore, you've got matches!!
あ～ 竜宮城で
ｳﾊｳﾊの夏休み 過ごすはずが➡
We were supposed to have a wonderful
summer vacation at Ryugu Palace.
なんで こんなこと やってんだろ
ｵﾚたちは！
Why did this have to happen to us?
たまには こんなのも いいｱﾙ！
ｷｬﾝﾌﾟみたいｱﾙ！
Things like this are nice once
in a while. It's like camping.
ｷｬﾝﾌﾟって お前…➡
Camping? We might not
be able to get home.
もしかしたら 二度と こっから
帰れねえかもしんねえんだぞ！
さすがは ﾘｰﾀﾞｰだ！
どんな窮地にも動じず➡
Just as I expected of our leader.
She isn't upset by any predicament,
むしろ 楽しむくらいの気概を
持ち合わせているとは…｡
and, if anything, she's got
the guts to enjoy it.
それでこそ 侍だ！
You're a true samurai!!
I'm not a samurai. Don't touch me!
侍じゃねえよ！ 触んなよ！
(桂)銀時！ ｷｻﾏも 少しは
ﾘｰﾀﾞｰを見習ったら どうだ？
Gintoki, why don't you learn
a little from our leader?
ｷｻﾏときたら いつも いつも
くだらん愚痴ばかり たれおって｡
You always complain about silly things.
そんなに 現状に 不満があるなら
攘夷志士にでも なりな もう！
If you're really disappointed
with the status quo,
you should join the Anti-Foreigner
Faction! Honestly...
なんで 途中から
勧誘に 変わってんだよ！
Why are you suddenly trying
to get me to join you?
なんで お母さん口調なんだよ！
Why are you talking to me
as if you're my mother?
おい… あれ なんだ？
Hey, what's that?
巨大な箱…｡
It's a giant box.
どう見ても 人工物だぜ？
It looks manmade. Why is
this on a deserted island?
なんで こんなもんが
無人島に ありやがる？
Leader, don't touch it!!
ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ 触るな!!
Courage and recklessness are
two different things, leader.
勇気と無謀は 違うぞ ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ！
If you're a samurai, don't
charge in blindly.
侍ならば
むやみに 突っ込むのではなく➡
敵の恐ろしさを 知ったうえで➡
You need to have the strength
to stand up to your enemies
立ち向かう強さを
もたねばいかん！
with the knowledge of how
terrifying they are!!
You already touched it!!
思いっきり 触りましたけども!!
逃げろ 神楽!!
Run away...
Kagura!!
銀ちゃん！ ﾂﾞﾗ！
(桂)ﾂﾞﾗじゃない！ 桂だ！
Gin-chan!! Zura!!
I'm not "Zura." I'm "Katsura"!!
(咳き込む声)
なんだよ… この煙！
What is this smoke?!
おい！ 大丈夫か!?
(咳き込む声)
Hey, are you all right?
I'm not "All right." I'm "Katsura"!!
(桂)大丈夫じゃない…｡ 桂だ…｡
(神楽)銀ちゃん！ ﾂﾞﾗ！
Gin-chan!! Zura!!
大丈夫… えっ…！
Are you all right?
(神楽)だ…
誰ｱﾙか～!? お前ら～!!
Who are you?!
[To be continued...]
["The Older, The Wiser"]
[Gintoki and Katsura have turned into old men...
Because of the smoke from a treasure chest (?).]
[Otohime, ruler of the Ryugu Palace, has a plot that is slowly coming to fruition. Can the elderly group stop her?!]
[See you next time.]